#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/lalithsu (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Enterprise Software SaaS Strategy

## Languages

Gujarati (Limited Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
Tamil (Native or Bilingual)

#### **Patents**

Systems and methods for health information messages archiving

Methods and systems for automated assignment of protection to physical documents that are digitized

Flexible and scalable artificial intelligence and analytics platform with flexible content storage and retrieval

FLEXIBLE AND SCALABLE
ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE AND
ANALYTICS PLATFORM WITH
ADVANCED CONTENT ANALYTICS
AND DATA INGESTION

Method and system for enabling legacy patients clinical documents for open sharing

# Lalith Subramanian

Software Product and Engineering Executive San Francisco Bay Area

## Summary

Executive with track record of capital-efficient product innovation and launches, GTM planning and execution. Leadership experience ranging from fast-moving startup teams to GM of multi-product-line, \$300+MM P&Ls at complex, global organizations.

Deep expertise in information security(endpoint, forensics, eDiscovery), data governance, AI/ML, BPM/data integration, content management, ERP, regulated vertical solutions (Healthcare, Pharma/Lifesciences, Fin.Svcs.)

Proven success in building and leading distributed product management and engineering teams and managing global customer relationships. Significant experience with turnarounds and M&A of diverse complexity.

# Experience

Autodesk Global VP, Product and Engineering November 2022 - Present (2 years 6 months) San Francisco Bay Area

UC Santa Barbara
Member Of The Board Of Advisors
December 2021 - Present (3 years 5 months)
Santa Barbara, California, United States

Aktana Advisor 2014 - Present (11 years) San Francisco, CA

DocuSign Vice President, Product Development May 2020 - January 2023 (2 years 9 months)

San Francisco, California, United States

Led Engineering, Product for Al/ML initiatives (platform dev, application adoption) across DocuSign

Led development of DocuSign policies for Ethical Al as part of Trust program, covering transparency, explainability, privacy, fairness, etc.

Lead Product and Engineering for DocuSign core (Foundations/Agreement Cloud platform)

Responsible for application hosting and ops (GCP)

Lead PM and Engineering for Security and reporting products (Manage)

Seal Software, a DocuSign Company EVP, Chief Product Officer September 2019 - January 2023 (3 years 5 months) Walnut Creek, CA

Leader in AI - driven document analytics utilized by major regulated industries for compliance reporting and contract lifecycle management (CLM.) Acquired by DocuSign, Inc.(NMS:DOCU)

- Lead Product, Engineering, cloud operations) and Sweden/Egypt development COEs

## OpenText

VP & Co-GM - Security, Analytics and Discovery business unit March 2016 - August 2019 (3 years 6 months) San Mateo

Lead product strategy/management and engineering for 3 businesses

- Security (Endpoint Security, Digital Forensics)
- AI, Analytics and Discovery (Text Mining, Magellan ML and analytics platform, federated search)
- LegalTech (eDiscovery review, Contract Analytics, legal document management)

with over \$300MM of revenue and global team of over 300-500 across 5 countries. Led diligence and integration of 3 public and private company acquisitions

**EMC** 

8 years

VIce President, Products & Solutions, Content Management Division April 2009 - October 2014 (5 years 7 months)

Pleasanton, CA

Spearheaded revenue growth through development and launch of new vertical SaaS solutions. Led cross-functional team consisting engineering, product management, marketing, and sales/services, launched Collaborative Healthcare offering that won two multi-million dollar nationwide SaaS deployments in first 2 years.

VP & GM, Information Governance Business 2006 - March 2009 (3 years)

Lead ~\$100MM global business around Information Governance (eDiscovery, records management, email archiving, etc.) and drive its rapid transformation to address emerging market trends - litigation readiness, SaaS, collaboration/social-media - particularly in regulated verticals such as Lifesciences, Financial Services, etc. Successfully launched completely revamped platform and applications - EMC SourceOne - in record time with a globally distributed product management and engineering team.

## EMC Software Group, EMC

Director, Enterprise Integrations & Emerging Technologies January 2004 - October 2006 (2 years 10 months)

Led engineering and technical product management team for enterprise data and content integration product line, including integration with SAP, Siebel, Salesforce, etc.

Built onshore+offshore team and launched new products for SAP in record time, driving 10x ARR growth. Products deployed at most major life science companies, oil & gas producers and other industries.

Led evaluation, acquisition and integration of Dolphin gmbh, a european integration services provider, Acartus, a reports management and archiving specialist, and Captiva, a publicly traded leader in software for imaging.

Documentum, Inc. Architect, Director of Engineering, Office of CTO 1995 - 2004 (9 years)

Led engineering of multiple generations of Documentum's eBusiness product line through hyper-growth phase, IPO and acquisition by EMC.

Responsible for build-buy evaluations, diligence and post-M&A operations in related areas e.g. digital rights management (DRM), content syndication Led partner engineering team to develop integrations with strategic partners e.g. SAP, etc.

## Education

Stanford University Graduate School of Business Business Administration and Management, General · (2010 - 2010)

National Institute of Technology Tiruchirappalli B.Engineering

The Ohio State University MS, Engineering